<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ACF News Online</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beta-test.teaparty.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beta-test.teaparty.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:07:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Live-action &#8216;Little Mermaid&#8217; debut makes box office waves</title>
		<link>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/live-action-little-mermaid-debut-makes-box-office-waves/</link>
					<comments>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/live-action-little-mermaid-debut-makes-box-office-waves/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta-test.teaparty.org/?p=11</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Disney&#8217;s live-action version of ‘The Little Mermaid’ netted the top spot at North American box offices on its opening weekend, over the United States&#8217; Memorial Day holiday, industry watcher Exhibitor Relations reported Sunday. The remake of the 1989 animated tale of an underwater princess who gives up her voice in pursuit of true love on]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Disney&#8217;s live-action version of ‘The Little Mermaid’ netted the top spot at North American box offices on its opening weekend, over the United States&#8217; Memorial Day holiday, industry watcher Exhibitor Relations reported Sunday.</p>



<p>The remake of the 1989 animated tale of an underwater princess who gives up her voice in pursuit of true love on land, starring pop singer Halle Bailey and Melissa McCarthy, raked in $117.5 million in US and Canadian box offices and another $68 million internationally, Exhibitor Relations said.</p>



<p>Despite the number one spot, analyst David A Gross pointed out that the aquatic adventure&#8217;s debut does not represent the biggest opening weekend for a live-action Disney adaptation.</p>



<p>He recalled that 2019&#8217;s ‘The Lion King’ and 2017&#8217;s ‘Beauty and the Beast’ earned $191.8 million and $174.8 million respectively, over their opening weekends.</p>



<p>&#8220;During the last dozen years, Disney has built live-action remakes into a powerhouse phenomenon,&#8221; Gross wrote in the FranchiseRe newsletter.</p>



<p>Still, Ariel and friends were able to bump last week&#8217;s number one feature ‘Fast-X’ down to a distant number two, with Universal&#8217;s action film pulling in only $29.5 million in the Friday to Monday period.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s less than half of what the movie, part of the ‘Fast &amp; Furious’ franchise starring Vin Diesel, made during its opening weekend last week.</p>



<p>Disney&#8217;s ‘Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3’ and Universal&#8217;s ‘The Super Mario Bros Movie’ were also knocked down one spot each from last weekend to take third and fourth places, making $25.3 million and $7.7 million.</p>



<p>In fifth place was Sony&#8217;s new action comedy ‘The Machine’, which earned $5.8 million and is based on US comedian Bert Kreischer&#8217;s stand-up routine.</p>



<p>Rounding out the top 10 were, ‘About My Father’ ($5.3 million), ‘Kandahar’ ($3 million), ‘You Hurt My Feelings’ ($1.8 million), ‘Evil Dead Rise’ ($1.2 million) and ‘Book Club: The Next Chapter’ ($1.2 million).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/live-action-little-mermaid-debut-makes-box-office-waves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PSG goalkeeper Rico in &#8216;serious&#8217; condition after horse riding accident</title>
		<link>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/psg-goalkeeper-rico-in-serious-condition-after-horse-riding-accident/</link>
					<comments>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/psg-goalkeeper-rico-in-serious-condition-after-horse-riding-accident/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta-test.teaparty.org/?p=8</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Paris Saint-Germain back-up goalkeeper Sergio Rico is in &#8220;serious&#8221; condition after a horse-riding accident, the French club confirmed Sunday. The 29-year-old Spaniard was on the bench for PSG as they won the Ligue 1 title on Saturday with a 1-1 draw at Strasbourg before heading to Spain, where the accident happened in El Rocio in]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Paris Saint-Germain back-up goalkeeper Sergio Rico is in &#8220;serious&#8221; condition after a horse-riding accident, the French club confirmed Sunday.</p>



<p>The 29-year-old Spaniard was on the bench for PSG as they won the Ligue 1 title on Saturday with a 1-1 draw at Strasbourg before heading to Spain, where the accident happened in El Rocio in Andalusia.</p>



<p>&#8220;He is in serious condition,&#8221; said a PSG spokesperson, while Spanish newspaper Marca report he is &#8220;stable&#8221;.</p>



<p>Rico was taken by helicopter to Seville&#8217;s Virgen del Rocio hospital, where he was placed on life support, according to local TV channel Canal Sur, citing medical sources.<br>&#8220;Lots of strength and a speedy recovery,&#8221; wrote Sevilla, whom he played for previously, on Twitter.</p>



<p>PSG tweeted their support for Rico and said they were &#8220;staying in contact with his family. The entire Red and Blue community offer them their support.&#8221;</p>



<p>Rico, born in Seville, won two Europa Leagues with his hometown side before moving on loan to Premier League side Fulham in 2019.</p>



<p>The goalkeeper then moved to PSG on loan in 2019 before making the move permanent in 2020.</p>



<p>Rico was loaned by the French side to Mallorca in January 2022, before returning to PSG for the current campaign.</p>



<p>He has made 24 appearances for PSG and has been capped once by the Spanish national team.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/psg-goalkeeper-rico-in-serious-condition-after-horse-riding-accident/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>North Korea informs Japan of upcoming &#8216;satellite launch&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/north-korea-informs-japan-of-upcoming-satellite-launch/</link>
					<comments>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/north-korea-informs-japan-of-upcoming-satellite-launch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta-test.teaparty.org/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[North Korea has informed Japan that is preparing to launch a satellite as early as this week, Tokyo announced Monday but warned it may actually be a sanctions-defying ballistic missile test. North Korea informed Japan that it will launch a rocket between May 31 and June 11, identifying waters near the Yellow Sea, the East]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>North Korea has informed Japan that is preparing to launch a satellite as early as this week, Tokyo announced Monday but warned it may actually be a sanctions-defying ballistic missile test.</p>



<p>North Korea informed Japan that it will launch a rocket between May 31 and June 11, identifying waters near the Yellow Sea, the East China Sea and to the east of Luzon Island in the Philippines as warning areas, a Japanese coast guard spokesman told AFP.</p>



<p>Such zones are usually designated for falling debris or rocket stages.</p>



<p>Japanese prime minister Fumio Kishida told officials to gather intelligence &#8220;on North Korea&#8217;s notification about the launch of a ballistic missile that it describes as a satellite&#8221;, his office said in a tweet.</p>



<p>&#8220;Even if it&#8217;s described as a satellite, a launch using ballistic missile technology would be a violation of United Nations Security Council resolutions&#8221; and would threaten people&#8217;s safety, Kishida told reporters.</p>



<p>In 2012 and 2016, Pyongyang tested ballistic missiles that it called satellite launches. Both flew over Japan&#8217;s southern Okinawa region.</p>



<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un this month inspected the country&#8217;s first military spy satellite as it was prepared for launch, and gave the green light for its &#8220;future action plan&#8221;.</p>



<p>In 2021, Kim had identified the development of such satellites as a key defence project for the North Korean military.</p>



<p>Because long-range rockets and space launchers share the same technology, analysts say developing the ability to put a satellite in orbit would provide Pyongyang with cover for testing banned intercontinental ballistic missiles (ICBMs).</p>



<p>Japan&#8217;s defence ministry issued an order to shoot down any ballistic missile confirmed to be on course to fall into its territory.</p>



<p>South Korea&#8217;s foreign ministry condemned the launch plan, but officials did not confirm to AFP if Seoul had been directly notified too.</p>



<p>&#8220;North Korea&#8217;s so-called &#8216;satellite launch&#8217; is a serious violation of UN Security Council resolutions banning all launches using ballistic missile technology, and is a clearly illegal act that cannot be justified under any pretext,&#8221; the ministry said.</p>



<p>South Korea and Japan have been working to mend long-frayed ties, including with greater cooperation on North Korea&#8217;s military threats.</p>



<p>Unusual stance<br>Meanwhile, Kishida on Monday reiterated that Tokyo is open to talks with Pyongyang.</p>



<p>North Korean state media on Monday published a statement from the country&#8217;s vice-minister of foreign affairs, appearing to endorse a conciliatory approach to relations with Japan &#8212; an unusual stance from Pyongyang.</p>



<p>If Japan avoids &#8220;being shackled by the past, and seeks a way out for improving the relations, there is no reason for the DPRK and Japan not to meet&#8221;, said the statement from Pak Sang Gil, using the initials of North Korea&#8217;s official name.</p>



<p>Pak said, however, that Japan needs to move on from sticking points such as the &#8220;abduction issue&#8221; for ties to improve.</p>



<p>Japan suspects dozens of people who are still missing were abducted by North Korean agents in the 1970s and 1980s to train spies in the Japanese language and culture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/north-korea-informs-japan-of-upcoming-satellite-launch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
