<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>International &#8211; ACF News Online</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beta-test.teaparty.org/category/international/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beta-test.teaparty.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:04:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>North Korea informs Japan of upcoming &#8216;satellite launch&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/north-korea-informs-japan-of-upcoming-satellite-launch/</link>
					<comments>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/north-korea-informs-japan-of-upcoming-satellite-launch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta-test.teaparty.org/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[North Korea has informed Japan that is preparing to launch a satellite as early as this week, Tokyo announced Monday but warned it may actually be a sanctions-defying ballistic missile test. North Korea informed Japan that it will launch a rocket between May 31 and June 11, identifying waters near the Yellow Sea, the East]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>North Korea has informed Japan that is preparing to launch a satellite as early as this week, Tokyo announced Monday but warned it may actually be a sanctions-defying ballistic missile test.</p>



<p>North Korea informed Japan that it will launch a rocket between May 31 and June 11, identifying waters near the Yellow Sea, the East China Sea and to the east of Luzon Island in the Philippines as warning areas, a Japanese coast guard spokesman told AFP.</p>



<p>Such zones are usually designated for falling debris or rocket stages.</p>



<p>Japanese prime minister Fumio Kishida told officials to gather intelligence &#8220;on North Korea&#8217;s notification about the launch of a ballistic missile that it describes as a satellite&#8221;, his office said in a tweet.</p>



<p>&#8220;Even if it&#8217;s described as a satellite, a launch using ballistic missile technology would be a violation of United Nations Security Council resolutions&#8221; and would threaten people&#8217;s safety, Kishida told reporters.</p>



<p>In 2012 and 2016, Pyongyang tested ballistic missiles that it called satellite launches. Both flew over Japan&#8217;s southern Okinawa region.</p>



<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un this month inspected the country&#8217;s first military spy satellite as it was prepared for launch, and gave the green light for its &#8220;future action plan&#8221;.</p>



<p>In 2021, Kim had identified the development of such satellites as a key defence project for the North Korean military.</p>



<p>Because long-range rockets and space launchers share the same technology, analysts say developing the ability to put a satellite in orbit would provide Pyongyang with cover for testing banned intercontinental ballistic missiles (ICBMs).</p>



<p>Japan&#8217;s defence ministry issued an order to shoot down any ballistic missile confirmed to be on course to fall into its territory.</p>



<p>South Korea&#8217;s foreign ministry condemned the launch plan, but officials did not confirm to AFP if Seoul had been directly notified too.</p>



<p>&#8220;North Korea&#8217;s so-called &#8216;satellite launch&#8217; is a serious violation of UN Security Council resolutions banning all launches using ballistic missile technology, and is a clearly illegal act that cannot be justified under any pretext,&#8221; the ministry said.</p>



<p>South Korea and Japan have been working to mend long-frayed ties, including with greater cooperation on North Korea&#8217;s military threats.</p>



<p>Unusual stance<br>Meanwhile, Kishida on Monday reiterated that Tokyo is open to talks with Pyongyang.</p>



<p>North Korean state media on Monday published a statement from the country&#8217;s vice-minister of foreign affairs, appearing to endorse a conciliatory approach to relations with Japan &#8212; an unusual stance from Pyongyang.</p>



<p>If Japan avoids &#8220;being shackled by the past, and seeks a way out for improving the relations, there is no reason for the DPRK and Japan not to meet&#8221;, said the statement from Pak Sang Gil, using the initials of North Korea&#8217;s official name.</p>



<p>Pak said, however, that Japan needs to move on from sticking points such as the &#8220;abduction issue&#8221; for ties to improve.</p>



<p>Japan suspects dozens of people who are still missing were abducted by North Korean agents in the 1970s and 1980s to train spies in the Japanese language and culture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://beta-test.teaparty.org/north-korea-informs-japan-of-upcoming-satellite-launch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
